As patients,
كمرضى،
we usually remember the names of our doctors,
نحن نتذكر عادة أسماء أطبائنا،
but often we forget the names of our nurses.
ولكننا غالباً ننسى أسماء ممرضاتنا.
I remember one.
أنا أتذكر إحداهن.
I had breast cancer a few years ago,
كنت مصابة بسرطان الثدي منذ بضعة سنوات،
and somehow I managed to get through the surgeries
وبطريقة ما تمكنت من النجاة من العمليات الجراحية
and the beginning of the treatment just fine.
كان كل شيء على ما يرام في بداية العلاج.
I could hide what was going on.
كنت قادرة على أن أخفي ما كان يجري.
Everybody didn't really have to know.
لم يكن الجميع بحاجة لأن يعرفوا.
I could walk my daughter to school,
كان بإمكاني اصطحاب ابنتي للمدرسة،
I could go out to dinner with my husband;
كنت قادرة على الذهاب للعشاء مع زوجي،
I could fool people.
كنت قادرة على خداع الناس.
But then my chemo was scheduled to begin
ولكن كان من المقرر أن يبدأ العلاج الكيمائي
and that terrified me
وقد أرعبني ذلك
because I knew that I was going to lose every single hair on my body
لأنني كنت أعرف أنني كنت سأفقد كل شعرة على جسدي
because of the kind of chemo that I was going to have.
بسبب نوعية العلاج الكيمائي الذي كنت سأخضع له.
I wasn't going to be able to pretend anymore
لم يكن باستطاعتي الاستمرار بالتظاهر
as though everything was normal.
وكأن كل شيء كان طبيعياً.
I was scared.
كنت خائفة.
I knew what it felt like to have everybody treating me with kid gloves,
كنت أعرف شعور أن يعاملني الجميع بحرص بالغ،
and I just wanted to feel normal.
كنت أرغب في أن شعر أنني طبيعية.
I had a port installed in my chest.
تم صنع فتحة في صدري.
I went to my first day of chemotherapy,
ذهبت لأول يوم من العلاج الكيميائي،
and I was an emotional wreck.
وكانت مشاعري محطمة تماماً.
My nurse, Joanne, walked in the door,
دخلت ممرضتي (جوان) إلى الغرفة،
and every bone in my body was telling me to get up out of that chair
وكانت كل عظمة في جسدي تخبرني بأن أغادر الكرسي
and take for the hills.
وأن أهرب نحو الأفق.
But Joanne looked at me and talked to me like we were old friends.
لكن نظرت (جوان) إلي وتحدثت معي وكأننا أصدقاء قدامى.
And then she asked me,
ثم سألتني،
"Where'd you get your highlights done?"
"أين قمت بتلوين شعرك؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I was like, are you kidding me?
فخطر لي، هل تمزحين معي؟
You're going to talk to me about my hair when I'm on the verge of losing it?
هل ستتحدثين معي عن شعري وأنا على وشك أن أخسره؟
I was kind of angry,
كنت غاضبة نوعاً ما،
and I said, "Really? Hair?"
وقلت: "حقاً؟ الشعر؟"
And with a shrug of her shoulders she said,
حركت كتفيها بخفه وقالت لي:
"It's gonna grow back."
"سينمو مرة أخرى."
And in that moment she said the one thing I had overlooked,
أخبرتني في تلك اللحظة عن الشيء الوحيد الذي غفلت عنه،
and that was that at some point, my life would get back to normal.
وهي أن حياتي ستعود لطبيعتها في نقطة ما.
She really believed that.
هي كانت تؤمن بذلك.
And so I believed it, too.
ولذا، فقد آمنت بذلك أيضاً.
Now, worrying about losing your hair when you're fighting cancer
القلق من خسارة شعرك في حين أنك تكافحين ضد السرطان
may seem silly at first,
قد يبدو سخيفاً في البداية،
but it's not just that you're worried about how you're going to look.
لكن الأمر لا يتعلق فقط بالقلق من مظهرك فيما بعد.
It's that you're worried that everybody's going to treat you so carefully.
لكن أنك قلقة من أن الجميع سيعاملونك بحرص بالغ.
Joanne made me feel normal for the first time in six months.
جعلتني (جوان) أشعر أنني طبيعية لأول مرة منذ 6 أشهر.
We talked about her boyfriends,
تحدثنا عن أصدقائها الحميمين،
we talked about looking for apartments in New York City,
تحدثنا عن البحث عن شقق سكنية في (نيويورك)،
and we talked about my reaction to the chemotherapy --
تحدثنا عن ردة فعلي تجاه العلاج الكيميائي --
all kind of mixed in together.
كل هذه الأمور ممزوجة معاً.
And I always wondered,
ولطالما تساءلت،
how did she so instinctively know just how to talk to me?
كيف كانت تملك الغريزة لكي تعرف كيف تكلمني؟
Joanne Staha and my admiration for her
إعجابي ب (جوان ستاها)
marked the beginning of my journey into the world of nurses.
كان علامة البداية لرحلتي في عالم الممرضات.
A few years later, I was asked to do a project
بعد بضعة سنوات، طلب مني القيام بمشروع
that would celebrate the work that nurses do.
هدفه الاحتفال بما تقوم به الممرضات.
I started with Joanne,
بدأت مع (جوان)،
and I met over 100 nurses across the country.
قابلت أكثر من 100 ممرضة في أنحاء البلاد.
I spent five years interviewing, photographing and filming nurses
أمضيت 5 سنوات في مقابلة وتصوير وصنع فلم
for a book and a documentary film.
لكتابة كتاب وإنشاء فلم وثائقي.
With my team,
ومع فريقي،
we mapped a trip across America that would take us to places
خططنا لرحلة عبر أمريكا أخذتنا إلى مناطق
dealing with some of the biggest public health issues facing our nation --
تتعامل مع بعض أكبر المشاكل الصحية العامة التي تواجه بلدنا --
aging, war, poverty, prisons.
الشيخوخة والحرب والفقر والسجون.
And then we went places
ثم ذهبنا إلى أماكن
where we would find the largest concentration of patients
حيث يمكننا أن نجد أكبر تركيز للمرضى
dealing with those issues.
يعانون من هذه المشاكل.
Then we asked hospitals and facilities to nominate nurses
طلبنا بعدها من المستشفيات والمنشآت أن يرشحوا ممرضات
who would best represent them.
يمكنهن تمثيلهم بأفضل شكل.
One of the first nurses I met was Bridget Kumbella.
إحدى أول الممرضات اللواتي قابلتهن كانت (بريدجت كامبيلا).
Bridget was born in Cameroon,
ولدت (بريدجت) في (الكاميرون)،
the oldest of four children.
وهي أكبر أشقائها الأربعة.
Her father was at work when he had fallen from the fourth floor
كان والدها في العمل عندما سقط من الدور الرابع
and really hurt his back.
وآذى ظهره بشدة.
And he talked a lot about what it was like to be flat on your back
وتحدث كثيراً عما كان يعنيه أن تكون مسطحاً على ظهرك
and not get the kind of care that you need.
وألا تحصل على العناية التي أنت بحاجة لها.
And that propelled Bridget to go into the profession of nursing.
وهذا ما دفع (بريدجت) للدخول في عالم التمريض.
Now, as a nurse in the Bronx,
وهي الآن كممرضة في (برونكس)،
she has a really diverse group of patients that she cares for,
لديها مجموعة متنوعة بحق من المرضى الذين تقوم على رعايتهم،
from all walks of life,
من كل جوانب الحياة،
and from all different religions.
ومن مختلف الأديان.
And she's devoted her career to understanding the impact
وكرست حياتها المهنية لفهم تأثير
of our cultural differences when it comes to our health.
فروقاتنا الثقافية عندما يتعلق الأمر بصحتنا.
She spoke of a patient --
تحدثت معنا عن مريض --
a Native American patient that she had --
مريض أمريكي أصلي كان لديها --
that wanted to bring a bunch of feathers into the ICU.
أراد أن يحضر مجموعة من الريش إلى العناية المركزة.
That's how he found spiritual comfort.
هذه هي الطريقة التي وجد بها الراحة الروحية.
And she spoke of advocating for him
وتحدثت عن كيف دافعت عنه
and said that patients come from all different religions
وقالت إن المرضى يأتون من ديانات مختلفة
and use all different kinds of objects for comfort;
ويستخدمون أدوات مختلفة بحثاً عن الراحة،
whether it's a holy rosary or a symbolic feather,
سواء كانت مسبحة مقدسة أو ريشة رمزية،
it all needs to be supported.
يجب أن نستوعبها جميعاً.
This is Jason Short.
هذا (جايسن شورت).
Jason is a home health nurse in the Appalachian mountains,
(جايسن) هو ممرض صحة منزلية في جبال (أبالاشيان)،
and his dad had a gas station and a repair shop when he was growing up.
كان والده يملك محطة للوقود ومحل للتصليح عندما كان صغيراً.
So he worked on cars in the community that he now serves as a nurse.
ولذا عمل على إصلاح السيارات في المجتمع الذي يعمل كممرض به الآن.
When he was in college,
عندما كان في الكلية،
it was just not macho at all to become a nurse,
لم يكن يعتبر التمريض مهنة رجولية،
so he avoided it for years.
لذا تجنبها لسنوات.
He drove trucks for a little while,
قام بقيادة الشاحنات لبعض الوقت،
but his life path was always pulling him back to nursing.
ولكن مسار حياته كان دائماً يرجعه إلى التمريض
As a nurse in the Appalachian mountains,
وكممرض في جبال (أبالاشيان)،
Jason goes places that an ambulance can't even get to.
يذهب (جايسون) إلى مناطق لا تستطيع سيارات الإسعاف الوصول إليها.
In this photograph, he's standing in what used to be a road.
في هذه الصورة، هو يقف في ما كان طريقاً في السابق.
Top of the mountain mining flooded that road,
أعمال التنقيب في أعلى الجبل أغرقت الطريق،
and now the only way for Jason to get to the patient
والطريقة الوحيدة لكي يصل (جايسون) للمريض
living in that house with black lung disease
المصاب بداء الرئة السوداء والذي يعيش في ذاك المنزل
is to drive his SUV against the current up that creek.
هو أن يقود سيارته ذات الدفع الرباعي ضد التيار في ذلك الجدول.
The day I was with him, we ripped the front fender off the car.
نزعنا الصدام الأمامي من سيارته عندما ذهبت معه يوماً.
The next morning he got up, put the car on the lift,
صباح اليوم التالي، قام بوضع سيارته على رافع،
fixed the fender,
وأعاد تركيب الصدام،
and then headed out to meet his next patient.
ثم غادر متوجهاً لزيارة مريضه التالي.
I witnessed Jason caring for this gentleman
شاهدت (جايسون) وهو يرعى هذا الرجل
with such enormous compassion,
مظهراً رحمة جمة،
and I was struck again by how intimate the work of nursing really is.
ثم صدمت مرة أخرى بحقيقة كيف أن التمريض هو عمل حميمي بحق.
When I met Brian McMillion, he was raw.
عندما قابلت (براين ماكميليان) كان قليل الخبرة.
He had just come back from a deployment
كان قد عاد لتوه من الخدمة العسكرية
and he hadn't really settled back in to life in San Diego yet.
ولم يعتد بعد على الحياة في (سان ديوغو).
He talked about his experience of being a nurse in Germany
تحدث عن خبرته كممرض في ألمانيا
and taking care of the soldiers coming right off the battlefield.
وعن رعايته للجنود الذي قد رجعوا للتو من المعارك.
Very often, he would be the first person they would see
غالباً ما يكون هو أول شخص يرونه
when they opened their eyes in the hospital.
عندما يفتحون أعينهم في المستشفى.
And they would look at him as they were lying there,
وينظرون إليه وهم راقدون،
missing limbs,
فاقدي الأطراف،
and the first thing they would say is,
وأول شيء يقولونه هو،
"When can I go back? I left my brothers out there."
"متى يمكنني الرجوع؟ لقد تركت إخوتي هناك."
And Brian would have to say,
ويكون (براين) مضطراً لأن يقول،
"You're not going anywhere.
"أنت لن تذهب لأي مكان.
You've already given enough, brother."
لقد قدمت الكفاية، يا أخي."
Brian is both a nurse and a soldier who's seen combat.
(براين) هو ممرض وجندي وقد عاش الحالتين.
So that puts him in a unique position
وهذا يضعه في موقف فريد
to be able to relate to and help heal the veterans in his care.
يتيح له التواصل ومساعدة المحاربين القدامى الذين في رعايته.
This is Sister Stephen,
هذه الأخت (ستيفن)،
and she runs a nursing home in Wisconsin called Villa Loretto.
وهي تدير دارً للتمريض في (ويسكونسون) تسمى (فيلا لوريتو).
And the entire circle of life can be found under her roof.
ويمكنك أن تجد دورة الحياة بكاملها في تلك الدار.
She grew up wishing they lived on a farm,
ترعرعت وهي تتمنى أن تعيش في مزرعة
so given the opportunity to adopt local farm animals,
لذا عما أتيح لها تبني حيوانات المزارع المحلية،
she enthusiastically brings them in.
أحضرتهم لدارها بكل حماسة.
And in the springtime, those animals have babies.
وتلد هذه الحيوانات صغارها في وقت الربيع.
And Sister Stephen uses those baby ducks, goats and lambs
وتستخدم الأخت (ستيفن) صغار البط والماعز والخراف
as animal therapy for the residents at Villa Loretto
للمعالجة مع الحيوانات لقاطني (فيلا لوريتو)
who sometimes can't remember their own name,
الذين في بعض الأحيان لا يقدرون على تذكر أسمائهم،
but they do rejoice in the holding of a baby lamb.
ولكنهم يفرحون حين يمسكون الخراف الصغيرة.
The day I was with Sister Stephen,
في اليوم الذي كنت فيه مع الأخت (ستيفن)،
I needed to take her away from Villa Loretto
احتجت أن آخذها بعيداً عن (فيلا لوريتو)
to film part of her story.
لكي أصور جزءاً من قصتها.
And before we left,
وقبل أن نغادر،
she went into the room of a dying patient.
ذهبت إلى غرفة مريض يحتضر.
And she leaned over and she said,
مالت نحوه ثم قالت له،
"I have to go away for the day,
"يجب أن أذهب بعيداً اليوم،
but if Jesus calls you,
ولكن إن ناداك المسيح،
you go.
فاذهب.
You go straight home to Jesus."
اذهب نحو المنزل مع المسيح."
I was standing there and thinking
كنت أقف هناك وأفكر
it was the first time in my life
لقد كانت المرة الأولى في حياتي
I witnessed that you could show someone you love them completely
شهدت أنه يمكنك أن تشعر شخصاً ما بحبك الكلي
by letting go.
عندما تتركهم يذهبون.
We don't have to hold on so tightly.
لا يجب أن نتمسك بشده.
I saw more life rolled up at Villa Loretto
شهدت وفاة العديد من الأشخاص في (فيلا لوريتو)
than I have ever seen at any other time at any other place in my life.
أكثر مما شهادته في أي وقت مضى وفي أي مكان آخر في حياتي.
We live in a complicated time when it comes to our health care.
نحن نعيش في أوقات معقدة عندما يتعلق الأمر برعايتنا الصحية.
It's easy to lose sight of the need for quality of life,
من السهل أن ننشغل عن جودة حياتنا،
not just quantity of life.
وليس فقط عدد الأحياء.
As new life-saving technologies are created,
ومع صناعة تكنولوجيا قادرة على إنقاذ الحياة،
we're going to have really complicated decisions to make.
فإننا سنواجه قرارات معقدة بحق يجب أن نتخذها.
These technologies often save lives,
هذه التقنية غالباً ما تنقذ الحياة،
but they can also prolong pain and the dying process.
ولكنها أيضا يمكنها إطالة الشعور بالألم وإطالة منازعة الموت.
How in the world are we supposed to navigate these waters?
كيف بحق السماء يمكننا خوض مثل هذه الأسئلة؟
We're going to need all the help we can get.
سنكون بحاجة لجميع المساعدة التي قد تتاح لنا.
Nurses have a really unique relationship with us
تتمتع الممرضات بعلاقات مميزه بالفعل معنا
because of the time spent at bedside.
بسبب الوقت الذي قضوه بجانب أسرتنا.
During that time,
خلال ذلك الوقت،
a kind of emotional intimacy develops.
تطور نوع من القرب العاطفي.
This past summer, on August 9,
الصيف الماضي، التاسع من أغسطس،
my father died of a heart attack.
توفي والدي نتيجة أزمة قلبية.
My mother was devastated,
كانت أمي متحطمة،
and she couldn't imagine her world without him in it.
لم تكن تتخيل عالمها دون وجوده معها.
Four days later she fell,
بعد أربعة أيام وقعت،
she broke her hip,
وكسرت وركها،
she needed surgery
واحتاجت لجراحة
and she found herself fighting for her own life.
ووجدت نفسها تكافح لكي تنقذ حياتها هي.
Once again I found myself
وجدت نفسي مرة أخرى
on the receiving end of the care of nurses --
أتلقى الرعاية من الممرضات
this time for my mom.
هذه المرة من أجل أمي.
My brother and my sister and I stayed by her side
بقيت أنا وأختي وأخي بجانب سريرها
for the next three days in the ICU.
للثلاثة أيام التالية في العناية المركزة.
And as we tried to make the right decisions
حاولنا اتخاذ القرارات الصحيحة
and follow my mother's wishes,
والاستماع لرغبات أمنا،
we found that we were depending upon the guidance of nurses.
وجدنا أنفسنا نعتمد على توجيهات الممرضات،
And once again,
ومرة أخرى،
they didn't let us down.
لم يخذلونا.
They had an amazing insight in terms of how to care for my mom
كان لديهم معرفة كبيرة لكيفية رعاية أمي
in the last four days of her life.
خلال الأيام الأربعة الأخيرة من عمرها.
They brought her comfort and relief from pain.
وفروا لها الراحة والاطمئنان من الألم.
They knew to encourage my sister and I to put a pretty nightgown on my mom,
عرفوا كيف يشجعوني وأختي لكي نلبس أمي ثوب النوم الجميل،
long after it mattered to her,
لفترة طويلة من بعد لم يعد لذلك أهمية،
but it sure meant a lot to us.
ولكنه بالتأكيد كان يعني لنا الكثير.
And they knew to come and wake me up just in time for my mom's last breath.
كما علموا أن يحضروا ويوقظوني لكي أحضر أنفاس أمي الأخيرة.
And then they knew how long to leave me in the room
كانوا يعرفون الوقت اللازم ليتركوني لوحدي في الغرفة
with my mother after she died.
مع أمي بعد أن توفيت.
I have no idea how they know these things,
ليست لدي أدنى فكرة كيف عرفوا تلك الأشياء،
but I do know that I am eternally grateful
ولكنني أعلم أنني ممتنه لهم بشكل غير محدود
that they've guided me once again.
لأنهم قاموا بتوجيهي مرة أخرى.
Thank you so very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)